<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Metrics Toolkit</title>
    <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Metrics Toolkit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This site is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Altmetric Attention Score</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/almetric_attention_score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/almetric_attention_score/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Altmetric Attention Score   Can Apply To Journal articles, books and chapters, preprints, datasets and any other research output deposited to a repository that the company tracks   Metric Definition &amp;ldquo;The Altmetric Attention Score is an automatically calculated, weighted count of all of the attention a research output has received [online, in sources tracked by Altmetric].&amp;rdquo;   Metric Calculation The AAS takes into account the volume of attention received by a research output across a number of online attention sources (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/blog_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/blog_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Blog Mentions   Can Apply To Primarily articles, books, and other scholarly items with persistent identifiers, such as a DOI, Pubmed ID, or Handle   Metric Definition The number of times a scholarly output has been linked to from a blog.   Metric Calculation Blog mentions are comprised of raw counts of links to outputs, from blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations, Books and book chapters</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/citations_books_bookchapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/citations_books_bookchapters/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Citations, Books and Book Chapters   Can Apply To Scholarly monographs and trade books, and chapters of scholarly monographs   Metric Definition The number of times that a book or chapter has appeared in the reference list of other articles and books.   Metric Calculation Many citation databases use a combination of text-mining and manual classification to build their lists of citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads, Books and book chapters</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_books_bookchapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_books_bookchapters/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Downloads, Books and Book Chapters   Can Apply To Books and book chapters   Metric Definition A download is an event triggered by a user clicking on the download button, in contrast to simply viewing a web page.   Metric Calculation A count of downloads over a period of time.   Data Sources Publishers, subject repositories, and institutional repositories   Appropriate Use Cases Book and book chapter downloads can be used as a leading indicator or proxy for others intent to use, rather than actual usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Weighted Citation Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/field_weighted_citation_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/field_weighted_citation_impact/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Field Weighted Citation Impact   Can Apply To Primarily journal articles, but also other kinds of research outputs, such as book chapters and conference proceedings that are sufficiently covered by abstract and citation databases.   Metric Definition The Field Normalized Citation Impact (FNCI) is the ratio between the actual citations received by a publication and the average number of citations received by all other similar publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodreads: Ratings and reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/goodreads_ratings_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/goodreads_ratings_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Goodreads: Ratings and Reviews   Can Apply To Any book that has been added to the Goodreads catalog   Metric Definition A book’s overall rating is the average of all ratings provided by Goodreads users.   Metric Calculation Mathematical/quantitative definition of the metric (when available)   Data Sources Goodreads book pages   Appropriate Use Cases Reviews may provide qualitative evidence of impact upon the reviewer(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mendeley Readers</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/mendeley_readers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/mendeley_readers/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Mendeley Readers   Can Apply To Primarily journal articles, but also other types of research outputs, such as web pages, books and conference papers, which users add to their Mendeley reference libraries   Metric Definition The number of Mendeley users that have added a particular document to a Mendeley library. Aggregated demographic information, such as geographic location and discipline for Mendeley readers, are also available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monograph holdings</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_holdings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_holdings/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Monograph Holdings   Can Apply To Books   Metric Definition The number of libraries that own (“hold”) a book.   Metric Calculation Holdings counts are derived from national or international union library catalogues, such as OCLC WorldCat. The holdings count is calculated as the number of unique libraries that own a copy of a book.   Data Sources Library book holdings as represented in union catalogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monograph sales and rankings</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_sales_rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_sales_rankings/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Monograph Sales and Rankings   Can Apply To Books   Metric Definition Sales figures record the number of times a book has been purchased. Sales ranking is a derivative metric that demonstrates how well a book is selling in comparison to other books.   Metric Calculation Sales figures record the number of recent sales of individual titles across the data sources being tracked by the metric provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/news_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/news_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name News Mentions   Can Apply To Journal Articles, Books, Book Chapters, Preprints, Datasets   Metric Definition The number of mainstream online news and magazine outlets that reference a research output.   Metric Calculation Counts are determined by the number of news outlets that reference a specific research output. Metric sources use a variety of methods for recognizing and tracking mentions, such as searching for hyperlinks in news reports and full text searching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/policy_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/policy_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Policy Mentions   Can Apply To Primarily journal articles and books   Metric Definition The number of times a research output has been cited in policy documents from government bodies or NGOs.   Metric Calculation The total count of citations to a research output in the policy sources being tracked by the metric provider. Each provider tracks differing manually-curated lists of policy bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/twitter_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/twitter_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Twitter Mentions   Can Apply To Any scholarly product (e.g. journal article) shared on Twitter using a link   Metric Definition Twitter mentions include posts and retweets that reference a trackable scholarly product.   Metric Calculation Counts are determined by the number of registered Twitter users that tweet or retweet a post that links to a trackable scholarly product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia citations</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/wikipedia_citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/wikipedia_citations/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Wikipedia Citations   Can Apply To Primarily scholarly publications with a persistent identifier, such as a DOI   Metric Definition References to scholarly outputs in Wikipedia articles, which are linked to in order to support the the entry’s claims.   Metric Calculation The number of times a scholarly output has been referenced in Wikipedia articles. The specific tracking method is dependent on the metric source provider.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
