<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Attention, reach, or diffusion on Metrics Toolkit</title>
    <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/categories/attention-reach-or-diffusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Attention, reach, or diffusion on Metrics Toolkit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This site is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/categories/attention-reach-or-diffusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Altmetric Attention Score</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/almetric_attention_score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/almetric_attention_score/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Altmetric Attention Score   Can Apply To Journal articles, books and chapters, preprints, datasets and any other research output deposited to a repository that the company tracks   Metric Definition &amp;ldquo;The Altmetric Attention Score is an automatically calculated, weighted count of all of the attention a research output has received [online, in sources tracked by Altmetric].&amp;rdquo;   Metric Calculation The AAS takes into account the volume of attention received by a research output across a number of online attention sources (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads, Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_articles/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Downloads, Articles   Can Apply To Journal articles or other serial publications   Metric Definition A download is an event triggered by a user clicking on the download button, in contrast to simply viewing a web page.   Metric Calculation A count of downloads during a period of time.   Data Sources Publishers, subject repositories, institutional repositories, researcher profile systems, and altmetrics aggregators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads, Books and book chapters</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_books_bookchapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_books_bookchapters/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Downloads, Books and Book Chapters   Can Apply To Books and book chapters   Metric Definition A download is an event triggered by a user clicking on the download button, in contrast to simply viewing a web page.   Metric Calculation A count of downloads over a period of time.   Data Sources Publishers, subject repositories, and institutional repositories   Appropriate Use Cases Book and book chapter downloads can be used as a leading indicator or proxy for others intent to use, rather than actual usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads, Software</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/downloads_software/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Downloads, Software   Can Apply To Research software, scripts, code snippets   Metric Definition File downloads over a period of time.   Metric Calculation Most downloads are calculated in a straightforward manner (where the number of downloads is simply reported as-is), but others account for–and remove–downloads initiated by bots.   Data Sources Though almost any web platform that can host files (including researcher websites), the most common and reliable sources of research software download statistics are those reported by software hosting sites (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github: Forks, collaborators, watchers</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/github_forks_collaborators_watchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/github_forks_collaborators_watchers/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Github: Forks, Collaborators, Watchers   Can Apply To Any project content stored on Github.com, but primarily software and code.   Metric Definition Github “Forks” are created when a user makes a copy of a repository (i.e., a group of files). A “collaborator” is another Github user who is able to perform many actions on the files within the repository, including edits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monograph holdings</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_holdings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_holdings/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Monograph Holdings   Can Apply To Books   Metric Definition The number of libraries that own (“hold”) a book.   Metric Calculation Holdings counts are derived from national or international union library catalogues, such as OCLC WorldCat. The holdings count is calculated as the number of unique libraries that own a copy of a book.   Data Sources Library book holdings as represented in union catalogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monograph sales and rankings</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_sales_rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/monograph_sales_rankings/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Monograph Sales and Rankings   Can Apply To Books   Metric Definition Sales figures record the number of times a book has been purchased. Sales ranking is a derivative metric that demonstrates how well a book is selling in comparison to other books.   Metric Calculation Sales figures record the number of recent sales of individual titles across the data sources being tracked by the metric provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/news_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/news_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name News Mentions   Can Apply To Journal Articles, Books, Book Chapters, Preprints, Datasets   Metric Definition The number of mainstream online news and magazine outlets that reference a research output.   Metric Calculation Counts are determined by the number of news outlets that reference a specific research output. Metric sources use a variety of methods for recognizing and tracking mentions, such as searching for hyperlinks in news reports and full text searching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter mentions</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/twitter_mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/twitter_mentions/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Twitter Mentions   Can Apply To Any scholarly product (e.g. journal article) shared on Twitter using a link   Metric Definition Twitter mentions include posts and retweets that reference a trackable scholarly product.   Metric Calculation Counts are determined by the number of registered Twitter users that tweet or retweet a post that links to a trackable scholarly product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia citations</title>
      <link>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/wikipedia_citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.metrics-toolkit.org/metrics/wikipedia_citations/</guid>
      <description>Field Field Value     Name Wikipedia Citations   Can Apply To Primarily scholarly publications with a persistent identifier, such as a DOI   Metric Definition References to scholarly outputs in Wikipedia articles, which are linked to in order to support the the entry’s claims.   Metric Calculation The number of times a scholarly output has been referenced in Wikipedia articles. The specific tracking method is dependent on the metric source provider.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
